Finding Aid to the Patty Ratliff collection
Hoover Institution Archives
Patty Ratliff collection,
circa 1945-1970
82031
Ratliff, Patty, collector.
1 oversize box, 212 envelopes (21.5 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Photographs, printed matter, and miscellany, depicting political, social, and economic conditions in the Soviet Union.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1982.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Content of Collection
Photographs, printed matter, and miscellany, depicting political, social, and economic conditions in the Soviet Union, 1945-1970. Includes a few earlier photographs.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Soviet Union--Pictorial works.
Collection Contents
- 41 prints of automobiles, trucks and tractors being produced and in use. (Box 82031 - 10.A-V, Folder mA, m*EP)
- 21 prints of various modes of transportation. (Folder mB)
- 87 prints of construction scenes. (Folder mC, m*EQ)
- 217 prints of heavy industry. (Folder mD-mE, mDI-mDJ, m*ER-m*ES)
- 26 prints of power plants. (Folder mF)
- 17 prints of interiors of buildings (Folder mG)
- 547 prints of buildings and street scenes. (Folder mH-mL, mDV-mDY, m*ET-m*EX)
- 217 prints of heavy industry. (Folder mD-mE, mDI-mDJ, m*ER-m*ES)
- 26 power plants. (Folder mF)
- 17 prints of interiors of buildings. (Folder mG)
- 547 prints of buildings and street scenes. (Folder mH-mL, mDV-mDY, m*ET-m*EX)
- 75 prints of statues and monuments. (Folder mM, m*EY)
- 54 prints of river and harbor scenes (Folder mN, m*EZ)
- 251 prints of speakers at political, cultural, and educational gatherings. (Folder mO-mQ, m*FA-m*FB)
- 201 prints of people conversing at political cultural and educational gatherings. (Folder mR-mS, mDZ-mEA)
- 96 prints of political leaders, including many of Nikita Khrushchev. (Folder mT, mEB, m*FC)
- 115 prints of election scenes. (Folder mU, mDK)
- 105 prints of military units and parades. (Folder mV, mDL, m*FD)
- 128 prints of scientific cultural and educational exhibitions (Folder mW-mX, m*FE-m*FF)
- 147 prints of public celebrations and state occasions. (Folder mY-mZ, m*FG-m*FH)
- 7 prints of religious scenes. (Folder mAA)
- 27 prints of ballet dancers. (Folder mAB, m*FI)
- 27 prints of musical bands. (Folder mAC)
- 21 prints of ethnic band instruments. (Folder mAD)
- 56 prints of musical choruses. (Folder mAE, m*FJ)
- 257 prints of dramatic performances. (Folder mAF-mAH, mEC, m*FK-m*FL)
- 31 prints of backstage scenes at dramatic performances. (Folder mAI, m*FM)
- 393 prints of motion picture film scenes. (Folder mAJ-mAL, mDM)
- 67 prints of folk dancers. (Folder mAm, m*FN)
- 82 prints of opera performances (Folder mAN, m*of)
- 50 prints of orchestras. (Folder mAO, m*FP)
- 155 prints of painters and paintings. (Folder mAP-mAQ, m*FQ)
- 42 prints of pianists. (Folder mAR)
- 65 prints of sculptors and sculptures (Folder mAS)
- 219 prints of harvest scenes. (Folder mAT-mAAU, mDN, mEP, m*FT-m*FU)
- 32 prints of fishing and trapping. (Folder mAV, m*FV)
- 69 prints of professional people at work. (Folder mAW)
- 128 prints of scientists. (Folder mAX, mEQ, m*FW)
- 36 prints of the psychologist Ivan Pavlov and of Pavlovian psychological research. (Folder mAY)
- 125 prints of doctors and medical care. (Folder mAZ, mED)
- 43 prints of laboratory technicians. (Folder mBA)
- 179 prints of skilled workers at work. (Folder mBB-mBC)
- 95 prints of scenes of commerce and consumer goods. (Folder mBD, mEE)
- 8 prints of boys. (Folder mBE)
- 29 prints of young men. (Folder mBF, m*FX)
- 209 prints of amateur men, both notable individuals and representative types. (Folder mBG-mBH, mDO-mDP, m*FY)
- 53 prints of elderly men. (Folder mBI, m*FZ)
- 8 prints of girls. (Folder mBJ)
- 57 prints of young women. (Folder mBK)
- 47 prints of amture women, both notable individuals and representative types. (Folder mBL, m*GA)
- 8 prints of elderly women. (Folder mBM)
- 280 prints of groups of people engaged in assorted daily activities. (Folder mBN-mBQ, mDQ, mEF, m*GB-m*GC)
- =179 prints of audiences at political, cultural and educational gatherings. (Folder mBR-mBS, mEG, m*GD-m*GE)
- 81 prints of members of ethnic minorities. (Folder mBT, m*GF)
- 9 prints of wildlife. (Folder mBU)
- 70 prints of livestock on farms. (Folder mBV, m*GG)
- 12 prints of scenes in the production of poultry, eggs and butter. (Folder mBW)
- 78 prints of the cultivation of fruit and vegetables. (Folder mBX, m*GH)
- 18 prints of circus performers. (Folder mBY, m*GI)
- 100 prints of scenes of family life. (Folder mBZ, mDR)
- 65 prints of dinner scenes in homes, dormitories and restaurants. (Folder mCA)
- 207 prints of people engaged in various leisure activities. (Folder mCB-mCC, mDS, mEH, m*GJ-m*GK)
- 63 prints of sanatoriums. (Folder mCD)
- 76 prints of chess players. (Folder mCE, mEI)
- 617 prints of sports scenes, including Olympic Games. (Folder mCF-mCK, mDT, mEJ-mEL, m*GL-m*GN)
- 1 print of kindergarten students. (Folder mCL)
- 74 prints of elementary school students and teaching. (Folder mCM, m*GO)
- 53 prints of secondary school students and teaching. (Folder mCN)
- 49 prints of university students and teaching. (Folder mCO, m*GP)
- 37 prints of scenes of adult education and vocational training. (Folder mCP)
- 204 prints of people reading books and magazines. (Folder mCQ-mCR, mEM-mEN, m*GQ)
- 113 prints of Young Pioneers. (Folder mCS, mEO, m*GR)
- 58 prints of scenes at the Cheliabinsk Tractor Works., 1958 (Folder mCT, mDU, m*GS)
- 13 prints of the reconstruction of Stalingrad at the end of World War II. (Folder mCU)
- 84 prints of scenes and delegates at the 21st extraordinary congress of the Communist Party of the Soviet Union, including visiting leaders of foreign communist parties., 1959 (Folder mCV, m*GT)
- 58 prints of the visit of Nikolai Bulganin and Nikita Khrushchev to Great Britain., 1956 (Folder mCW)
- 40 prints of sports events at the Spartakiada of the Nations of the USSR., 1956 (Folder mCX, m*GU)
- 46 prints of theatrical performances. (Folder mCY)
- 53 prints of hydroelectric power stations., 1956 (Folder mCZ, m*GV)
- 54 prints of educational scenes. (Folder mDA)
- 16 prints of various scenes in the Ukraine., 1964 (Folder mDB, m*GW)
- 28 color prints of various scenes in Minsk. (Folder mDC)
- 678 miscellaneous prints. (Folder mDD-mDH, m*GX-m*HB)